Joe Carlton

Full Stack Engineer

I am a Software Engineer with extensive experience working in startup environments to deliver timely, capable products and applications that best utilize the benefits of cloud computing. I excel in leading remote teams, serverless API's, JavaScript/TypeScript software development, ecommerce applications, and project management.

Work History

2020-09 -Current

Technical Lead Engineer

Provana, Inc., Remote

Led a team of three talented developers though efficiently and confidently delivering a cloud-based, cross-platform, ecommerce app from conception to \$20k+ in revenue in its first 2 months of focus group testing.

- Outlined work plans, determined resources, wrote timelines and generated initial budgets as part of project scope determination.
- Defined parameters for technical development tasks such as API and data acquisitions.
- Designed, coded, tested, debugged and documented programs and developer tooling using agile development practices.
- Implemented DevOps across deployment and testing strategies and application monitoring.
- Provided guidance and direction to less experienced staff in resolution of highly complex technical problems.
- Implemented and adopted cloud technologies and best practices for automation, configuration, monitoring and platform scalability.

2019-09 -2021-08

Systems Engineer

Fragadelphia, LLC, Philadelphia, PA
Designed, built, and managed on-premises systems

Contact

Address

Long Beach, CA, 90802

Phone

(734) 945-9666

E-mail

joe@rconjoe.com

Twitter

rcon_joe

LinkedIn

rconjoe

Skills

Cloud services



Software Development



System administration



Node/Typescript Specialist



Testing and debugging



API design knowledge



and networks for event/media production applications spanning 150+ workstations with in-house LAN.

- Forked an industry leading open source tool for server management and adapted it for the client's specific needs.
- Oversaw project scope installation and commissioning for compliance with specifications, project schedule and industry best practices and techniques.
- Performed installation, maintenance, and upgrades on servers and workstations.
- Developed volunteer policies and procedures, codes of conduct and volunteer standards.

Education

2019-09 -2021-02 No Degree: Project Management

University of California, Irvine - Irvine, CA

Affiliations

Underdog Devs: https://underdogdevs.org

- A community of software engineers supporting aspiring developers who come from disadvantaged backgrounds or who are formerly incarcerated
- UDD provides mentees with a stipend while they study full time with our mentors
- We try to lead people to jobs through industry contacts at the end of each cohort

Certifications

2020-04

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Interests

IoT and Device Management

E-bikes

Jazz

Project Management



Java/Spring



Go



Python



Pawn/Embedded languages



Software

JavaScript/TypeScript



Cloud API's and Services



DevOps + Developer tooling



Linux/Virtualization



Google Cloud
Platform/Firebase



Data Modeling



Vue.js

Very Good

NoSQL/Mongo/Dynamo /Firestore

Very Good

Ionic Framework

Good

Source Control Patterns

